Student:Hello.Last lecture we learned about recovery.
大家好 上节课我们学到了休整
At time,away from work really relax.
时不时地放下工作 放松一下自己
I'd like to invite you to join a traditional
我想邀请你们参加一项传统并且
and time-tested recovery period,Shiva,the Jewish sabbath.
有历史渊源的休整节日 犹太安息日
This Friday night,
这周五的晚上
Howard Hill and Hervat at Harvard invite you and your friends
哈佛的Howard Hill和Hervat将邀请大家
to Shiva dinner at the Mac for Shiva 1000.
来Mac中心享用犹太安息日大餐
Come for free dinner at the deck down Mac
欢迎来到Mac中心的露天平台
with all of your friends,
和你的朋友们一起享用免费大餐
where our very own professor Tal Ben-Shahar will be speaking.
我们的Tal Ben-Shahar教授将会发表讲话
Doors are open at 630,and dinner starts at 7.
中心将于六点半开门 晚餐七点开始
Please RSVP for this really fun event at Shiva1000.org.
如果想参加请迅速在Shiva1000.org上回复
Everyone is invited,so please sign up.
所有人都欢迎前来
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:Hi,good morning.
大家好
I was also asked to announce on behalf of the Women Softball team
我还被要求替女子垒球队通知大家
They would've been here and they would've announced themselves,
她们原本是要来这里通知大家的
but they are at the game and that was delayed.
但是她们现在正在进行比赛 一场被推迟了的比赛
There's a game this Sunday and...Saturday.Saturday and Sunday.
这周六和周日都有比赛
And also for the men's baseball team.
还有男子棒球队
So come out and cheer.And one more announcement.
所以请去为他们欢呼 还有一个通知
They can't hear.Sorry.Yeah.Yeah.
他们听不见 抱歉 好的
All right.So May 21,9:15- day for the final.
好的 就是5月21号 九点十五分开始决赛
Um hope you can make it.
希望你们能过去看看
OK.It's a Monday.All right.
是周一 好的
So every year when I teach the perfectionism lecture,
每年只要我一要讲完美主义的课
something happens.
就有点坏事要发生
So the first year,
第一年
I remember I actually forgot my computer at home.
我记得我是把电脑忘在了家里
Second time,the projector didn't work.
第二年 投影仪又坏了
And this year I forgot my power,
而这一年 我忘了带电源线了
my power for the computer at home.
把电源线忘在了家里
So hopefully it will last the entire semester.
所以希望这点电能支持一个学期
If not we'll just have to deal with the imperfect scenario,
如果不行的话我们就只能面对不完美了
but that's OK.
但是其实也没关系的
I think it must be something subconscious.
这肯定是潜意识里的问题
Because it's too much of a coincidence
因为这也太巧合了
that every time something happens.
每次都有这些事情发生
Walk the talk.
的确是这样
So where were we last time?
那么上次我们讲到哪了
Last time we talked about how you learned how to walk.
上次我们讲到你们是怎么学会走路的
We learned about how you learned to draw circles.
我们讲到你们是怎么学会画圆圈的
And all through failure.As Thomas Edison said,
都是通过不断地失败 如爱迪生所说
"I learned my way...I failed my way to success."
"我通过不断失败以至成功"
And we saw it with top athletes,
我们从那些最顶尖的运动员身上看到
whether it was Babe Ruth or Michael Jordan.
不管是Babe Ruth还是乔丹
We saw it with top business people,
我们也从最顶尖的生意人身上看到
whether it was Thomas Watson,IBM or Anita Roddick,
不管是IBM创始人Thomas Watson还是
founder of the,of Body Shop.
Anita Roddick 美体小铺的创始人
We see it with artist and scientist-
我们从艺术家和科学家身上看到
the most successful ones are also the ones who failed the most,
最成功的人也是失败最多的人
and these are the ones
而他们就是那些
who understand the value and the importance of failure.
深刻明白失败的价值与重要性的人
I guarantee you then none of them enjoy failing.
我向你们保证 他们没人喜欢失败
Failing hurts; it's disappointing at best;
失败让人受伤 让人极度失望
it's frustrating; it's embarrassing often.
让人沮丧 也经常使人尴尬
However,people who ultimately succeed recognize
但是 那些最为成功的人 都会
that value of failure and learning from it.
认识到失败和从失败中学习的价值
There's a wonderful book
有一本非常好的书
that came out recently by one of my mentors-
是由我的一位导师最近完成的
he taught at the business school for a few years;
他在商学院教了几年书
he is a professor
他是一名在
at University of Southern California- Warren Bennis.
南加州大学任职的教授 Warren Bennis
And Warren Bennis wrote a book,
Warren Bennis写了一本书
which is called "Geeks and Geezers".
名叫做《极客与怪杰》
And in the book,
在这本书里
he compared very successful leaders who were young,
他将非常年轻的顶多30岁出头的
early 30s and older generation leaders,
年轻成功人士和老一代的
people who have really made it,
真正有所成就的划时代领袖人物
big time leaders who are now in their 70s and 80s,sometimes 90s.
他们多在七十岁 八十岁甚至九十岁以上
And he compared these two groups:
他将两组人进行了对比
the geeks- the young ones; the geezers,the older ones.And
极客 指那些年轻的 怪杰 指年长的
what he found was that there were a number of very interesting
而他发现 有一些
and meaningful differences between the generations
非常有趣同时也很有意义的差异
of again highly successful late 20s or early 30 years old
存在于年轻的二十多到三十出头的成功人士
and highly successful older individuals.
和年长的成功领袖人物之间
One of the most notable differences was that work...
其中最明显的差异就是
work life balance,
工作与生活的平衡
which is very important for the late 20s,early 30s.
这对于年轻的成功人士来说非常重要
Very important- they talked about it constantly,
非常重要 他们自己也经常谈论这个
whereas for the 70 80 90 year olds,
但是对于年老一代的成功人士那里
it was almost a foreign concept.
这几乎完全就是一个外来观念
What does that even mean? Why?
这是什么意思啊 为什么会这样呢
Because they were at work usually 24/7.
因为他们总是处在工作中
All of them in that sample were men.
在那个样本中所有人都是男性
And the women were at home,taking care of the life part.
而女性则待在家里 负责生活的部分
So there was a work life balance- where they were doing the work,
所以说他们的工作与生活的平衡是
the wives were doing the life.
丈夫负责工作 妻子负责照顾生活
Whereas the younger generation,men and women in that sample
在年轻成功人士的样本里 男女都有
and talking about the work life balance.
那他们自然会谈论到工作与生活的平衡
There are a few other differences as well,
两代人之间还有其它的不同
but there is one similarity,
但是也有一个相同点
one thing that was common to both groups.
这一点对于两代人来说都是一样的
And that was at least one,
那就是有至少一次
usually more than one significant failure,
一般来说要多于一次的 显著的失败
what Warren Bennis came to call "a crucible",a real crisis
Warren Bennis称其为"考验" 一次灾难
whether it was a meaningful loss or losing a job being fired,
无论是重要的竞争失败 或者失去了工作
one's identity being insulted,loss of a person.
还是受到了屈辱 失去了亲人
Some real serious crucible,a failure.
一些严重的考验 一次失败的经历
That was common to both groups,
这是两代人都共同拥有的
and both groups thought that failure as a pivotal point,
他们都将失败看做一个关键点
as a turning point in their lives.
一个生活的转折点
Something that helped them become who they are today.
一些帮助造就今天的他们的因素
Again,not saying it happened for the best
再说一遍 我不是说已经发生的是好事
but they were able to make the best of that which happened.
而是他们能够好好利用已经发生的事
Now most people experience crucibles
每个人都会经历考验
throughout their lives,hardships,difficulties,
都会面临困难和阻碍
but difference between the highly successful people,
但是那些极度成功的人
for example the sample in Warren Bennis's book
如Warren Bennis的书里面写到的那些人
and many other people is that
和一般人的不同之处在于
they are able to make the best of what happens.
他们能够好好地利用已经发生的事情
They see it as an opportunity,
他们将这些事情看成机遇
a learning experience,a stepping stone.
一种学习的经历 一块垫脚石
The importance of failure for resilience,for well being as well.
这就是失败对于适应力与完善人格的作用
So let me move on and define what we mean by perfectionism.
我们继续来定义一下完美主义吧
Because there are many definitions
因为现在有很多的定义
and we throw that word around constantly.
我们经常提及这个词
But what do I actually mean by perfectionism?
但我要说的完美主义是什么
I define it as:
我的定义是
an incapacitating fear of failure that permeates our lives,
一种充斥在我们生活中的对失败的失能性恐惧
especially those areas that we care about most.
尤其是在我们最在意的方面
Note the word incapacitating.It is not just a fear of failure.
注意"失能性"这个词 不只是对失败的恐惧
OK I don't know a person who is not afraid of failure,
好吧 我也不认识哪怕一个不害怕失败
who is not embarrassed by it or feels frustrated by it.
也不会因为失败感到尴尬或沮丧的人
So that's natural.
这是很自然的
That's human- whether we like it or not.
这就是人性 不管我们喜欢不喜欢
But an incapacitating fear of failure is the failure
但对失败的失能性畏惧是
that is debilitating us,that stops us,that prevents us
一种让我们在面对问题的时候
from coping,from trying,from putting ourselves on the line.
裹足不前的的畏惧
And the other part that I want to highlight in this definition
而我要在这个定义里强调的另一点
is that "especially those areas that we care about most".
就是"尤其是我们最在意的方面"
You know,
你们也明白
I am not a perfectionist when it comes to playing Monopoly.
我在玩大富翁的时候可不是完美主义者
It's not that
这也不是因为...
It's competitive.
这的确很有竞争性
but it's not that important for me if I win or lose.
但是对于我来说胜败并不重要
But perfectionism was a central part of my life
但是完美主义确是我生活的重心
when it came to- as I mentioned earlier,
比如说 就如同我提到过的
squash which was very meaningful to me,
壁球对我而言非常重要
academics which is very meaningful to me,and
学术对我而言也非常重要
relationships which was and is a very important part of my life.
和别人的关系对我来说也非常重要
So in these areas,that's where I experienced perfectionism,
在这些方面 我就体会到了完美主义
and that's where I needed to do the work and still doing the work
也是在这些方面 我必须并且一直在努力
It's in those areas.Let me elaborate on this definition.
在这些方面 让我详细说明一下
It is an approach,a cognitive and emotional schema,
这是我们在面对人生的旅途的时候
that we hold toward the journey of our lives,
也是我们从A点到B点的过程中
toward the process of getting from point A to point B.
采取的一种方式 一种认知与情感的基模
The emphasis here is on journey.
重点在旅途上面
A person committed to excellence can still be as ambitious
一个追求卓越的人仍可能和完美主义者
and more ambitious than a perfectionist.
一样 或者比完美主义者更有野心
The difference between the two
两者之间的不同
is just their approach toward the journey.
在于他们面对旅途时的方式
Let me illustrate.So let's first take the perfectionist.
我来举个例子 首先是一个完美主义者
The perfectionist is currently at point A,
他正站在A点
wants to get to the point B.
他想到B点去
What's the perfect,most efficient path between the two points?
什么是最完美最有效率的方式呢
Straight line!
就是直的路线
This is the path- this is the cognitive and emotional schema
这就是路线 这就完美主义者在面对
that the perfectionist has when he or she looks at the journey,
旅途的时候抱有的认知与感情的基模
how they want to get from where they are now to where they want to get to.
怎么从起点到终点
A person committed to,to excellence,
一个追求卓越的人
as ambitious as the person,perfectionist,
和完美主义者一样雄心勃勃
wants to get from point A to point B.
也想从A点到B点去
No different here.What is different?
没什么不一样 不同之处在哪里
The cognitive schema that relates to the journey.
对于这段旅途 认知基模上的不同
The person committed to excellence understands
追求卓越的人明白
that while he improves,inevitably at some point,he would fail.
当他进步的时候 不可避免地会遭遇失败
A perfectionist understands that
一个追求卓越的人明白
sometimes she may not get the grade that she expected,
有时候她不一定能拿到她想要的分数
but she would learn from it.
但她会吸取教训
A perfectionist understands that in relationships
一个也明白在恋爱关系之中
there is no such thing as a perfect relationship
根本就没有完美的恋爱关系
and then therefore,he sometimes makes a mistake,
所以 他会犯错
so she sometimes makes a mistake,
她也会犯错
but they continue and they learn from it.
但他们都会不断吸取教训
And the relationship becomes,gets stronger.
然后他们的感情不断地变得更加坚固
And a perfectionist understands that
完美主义者明白
he needs to fail time and again-
他需要不断地失败
5 times,10 times,sometimes 10 thousand times
五次 十次 有时候一万次
as we saw with Edison until they get to the point B.
就如同我们了解的爱迪生的故事那样
As ambitious,but the schema is very different.
一样地野心勃勃 但是基模有所不同
I have to draw many failed circles
我必须画出许多不好的圆圈
before you get to that ideal circle that Vincent drew last time.
在你们画出Vincent上次画出的那个圆以前
And the question now becomes "so which is realistic?"
现在的问题是 哪个才更现实
Is it realistic to have that schema
拥有这样的基模是否现实
or is this one more realistic?
或者说这个才比较现实
Well,I think it's pretty obvious.
我想这是很明显的
There is no straight line toward success.
要达到成功可没有直线的捷径
There is no straight line toward a happy relationship.
要达成一段快乐的恋情也没有捷径
There is no straight line toward being inventing the light bulb,
要发明电灯泡也没有捷径
or being good at psychology,
学好心理学也没有
or being a good parent or a good friend.
想成为好的父母或者朋友也没有
We make mistakes.
我们会犯错
And "nature to be commanded must be obeyed."
而且 自然的规律我们必须遵守
Pursuing excellence is about a constraint view of nature.
追求卓越就是要克服困难
Yes,I wish that I could get from point A to point B in this way.
是啊 我也希望我能直接从A点到B点
I wish I were so.I didn't enjoy failing my generals;
我希望我能做到 我希望我不必经历失败
I didn't enjoy falling down many times and losing in squash.
我不喜欢不断地失败与打壁球输掉
I certainly don't enjoy disagreements with my wife.
我当然也不会喜欢和我妻子意见不合
However,I also would rather not have the law of gravity
我甚至宁愿没有万有引力定律
and be able to fly everywhere or float everywhere.
然后我就可以到处飞或者到处飘
This is.This is a fantasy.
这是现实 而这就是幻想了
And when we have this schema in our mind,
当我们心中存在着这样的基模的时候
we are putting ourselves,fighting nature,
我们就在让自己反抗自然规律
and just like we would lead an unhappy and frustrating life,
就如我们如果不接受万有引力定律的话
if we did not accept the law of gravity,
我们的生活就会充满不快与沮丧
we live and so many people live- so many people at Harvard,
我们活着 那么多人也活着 哈佛有不少人
not just at Harvard,everywhere are frustrated constantly,
不只是哈佛 所有地方都有 时常沮丧
because in their minds,they have this schema.
因为在他们心里 他们一直有这样的基模
And again,this does not mean that we enjoy failure.
再说一遍 这并不是说我们该享受失败
But when we have this schema,
但当我们有这样的基模的时候
in addition to not enjoying failure,
同时又不享受失败
we have the frustration of not accepting reality.
我们就会因为难以接受事实而沮丧
Now there are consequences to having this schema.
拥有这样的基模也会有后果的
I want to discuss some of these consequences
我就想讨论一下这样的后果
and some of the characteristics of a person who holds this schema
怀有拥有这样的基模的人的一些特征
Now there is no perfect perfectionist.
根本就没有完美的完美主义者
As I said,we all exist somewhere along the continuum.
就如我说的 我们都存在于一个闭区间内
And there are many people,
确实有一些人
again,many people here were closer to this end of the continuum.
确实有很多人更接近这个区间的这端
The characteristics that I'd like to share with you are all ones
我想和你们分享的这些特征 都是那些
that are documented in literature.
已经被记载于文学作品之内的
There are many people who have them.
有很多人都拥有这样的特征
You will identify with some of the characteristics,
你们大家或多或少都具有一些这样的特征
not with others.
而不是别的特征
That's fine.
这也没关系的
All the characteristics in addtion to being well documented in
所有的这些特征 除了都已被心理学著作
the psychological literature are also ones that I experienced,
详述以外 我也都有过体会
or still experience.
或者现在仍有所体会
So these ones are personally meaningful to me,
所以这些特征对我来说具有一定的意义
in addtion to being also quite common.
它们本身也非常常见
The first one: defensiveness.
第一个是 自卫性
In arguments,in discussions,perfectionists are defensive.
在争论和讨论中 完美主义者都有自卫性
Why? Because a criticism is by definition a deviation
为什么 因为批评在定义上就是一种
from a straight line.
对于完美的直线方式的偏离
It's imperfection.It's a daint.
这就是不完美 是一种挑刺
It's something that maybe I'm not doing perfectly well.
就是我没做得完美的事情
And we don't like deviations from a schema we have.
我们都不喜欢偏离我们所持基模的东西
Remember,the mind doesn't like when there is an inconsistency
记住了 我们的心是不喜欢内在与外在
between what is inside and what is outside.
之间的脱节的
We want there to be a balance,congruence.
我们需要的是平衡 一致
We don't like desinence.
我们不喜欢横生枝节
And if what we have in mind is the perfecionist schema,
而如果我们心中抱有的是完美主义基模
the criticism is a deviation from it.
而批评又是对其的偏离
And then we become defensive.
那我们就会变得有自卫性
Again,something that I experience numerously times;
这是我多次有所感受的
something that I'm working on constantly.
并且也是我一直在努力解决的
In addition,or in constrast,
附带一提 或者说是正好相反
a person committed to excellence is open,
一个追求卓越的人是心胸开阔的
is welcoming of suggestions and criticisms at times.
他会欢迎时不时的建议与批评
It doesn't mean that he or she enjoys it,
这不是说他或者她喜欢这样
but he or she understands that it's necessary,
而是他或她明白这是必要的
that it's an important part of growth,of development.
这是成长与发展的重要部分
Perfectionist focuses on the half empty part of the glass.
完美主义者只注意到空着的那半个杯子
Why? Because a perfectionist is obssessed by failure,
为什么 因为完美主义者为失败所困扰
obssessed by deviations from that straight narrow.
被对直线完美方式的偏离所困扰
And whatever it is,what are obssessed with by definition
而不管是什么 困扰我们的
is what we constantly focus on.
就是我们所关注的
So he or she constantly fosues on what is not working,
他或她一直关注未能达成的东西
on potential failures or actual failures.
关注潜在的可能失败或者是真正的失败
Person committed to excellence
追求卓越的人
focuses on the half full part of the glass.
则会专注于已经满的那半个杯子
How? Because he or she enjoys getting to where he or she is going
为什么 因为他或她既享受达成目标
but also learns to enjoy every step of the way- the journey,
又学会享受过程中的每一步 那就是旅途
even failure is an opportunity.
即便是失败也能是机遇
Person com...A perfectionist over generalizes,catastrophizes.
完美主义者会过度一般化 夸大化问题
It's all or nothing.Either I'm perfect,or I'm a failure.
非黑即白 我要么是完美的 要么一无是处
And we'll see the consequences
我们等一下就能看到
in a minute of this "all or nothing" approach.
这样的"全部或没有"的对立于现实的方法
Versus realistic.
造成的后果
Again,realizing what reality looks like,
我们又谈到了 明白现实是什么样的
what progress in essence looks like.
明白事物的过程是怎么样的
For perfectionist,there is no self-acceptance.
对于完美主义者来说 是没有自我接受的
A person committed to excellence-
对于追求卓越的人来说
there is acceptance first of all of reality as comprising spirals
能够接受现实中存在的各种弯路
rather than a straight line.
而没有一步登天的捷径
Acceptance of personal failure
能够接受个人的失败
and the acceptance of the self as a whole.
能够将自己视作一个整体予以接受
Perfectionist- there is one way and that's the highway.
对完美主义者来说 只有一种方式是合适的
It is a static.
并且是固定不变的
There is no improvization; there is no deviation;
没有任何提升的空间 也没有丝毫偏离
there is no trial and error.
更没有问题和错误
There is just one way in contrast to having much more dynamic,
只有一种方式 而不是更为动态性的
flexible process and journey,with much more sponetaneity,
更有弹性与自发性的过程与旅途
which manifests itself of course in behaviors.
在行为中自我证实
A perfectionist is terrified to failure- terrified that failure
完美主义者恐惧失败 恐惧来自于内心的
from within that he or she perceives themselves as failures
自己将自己视为失败者的失败
but also that others see him or her as a failure.
也恐惧他人将自己视为失败者
Keeping that fa?ade,that image of impregnability of perfection.
就是为了维持那种完美的幻觉
Versus failure as feedback.Again,not enjoying failure.
而不是将失败视为反馈 不是说要享受失败
I haven't met a person who does enjoy failing,
我还没遇到过享受失败的人
but seeing it more as feedback,as a growth opportunity.
而是要将失败视为一种反馈和成长的机会
A perfectionist is all about getting here.
完美主义者只想着怎么到达这里
That's what it's about.This is a means toward an end.
他们只关注这个 只针对目的
Tangential.
直来直去的
Something that is not important
别的事情根本不重要
other than taking me from here to here.
如果它不能让我达到目的的话
Or as for person committed to excellence,
但对于追求卓越的人来说
the journey is much part of the success as the destination.
旅途和终点都是成功的一部分
Now there are numerous,numerous consequences to this distinction
这样的基模上的差异
to holding one schema versus the other.
会导致很多的后果
Here are some of them.
我在这里列举一些
The first one is that a perfectionist experiences only,
第一个 就是完美主义者只能感受到
at best,temporary relief.
最多也只是 暂时性的轻松
So yes,
是的
there are constant pressure but when he or she gets to point B,
他们会感受到持续的压力 但当他们
then they feel relieved.
达到目的之后 他们感到了轻松
This is essentially the consummate rat racer.
这就是典型的逐利者
Let me give you an example of such a rat racer.
我来给你们一个这样的逐利者的例子
The person- let's call him X-
一个人 我们姑且称他为X先生
goes to school,goes to an elementary school.
去上学了 上小学
Until that point,
在那之前
he really enjoyed his day care,pre-K,kindergarten.
他一直很享受学前的生活
And then he goes to school and the pressure begins.
而他上学以后就开始有压力了
Because he begins to understand he really needs to work very hard
因为他明白 他必须很努力地读书
and do extremely well if he is to get into a good middle school.
并取得非常好的成绩来上一个好初中
Because the middle school that his parents want him to go to
因为他父母想让他进的那间初中
is very competitive,very tough to get into.
竞争很激烈 非常不好进
And he did get into a very good elementary school.
他确实进了一间不错的小学
But now he has to do the same for middle school.
但是现在他要为初中而努力了
So the pressure mounts.And he doesn't really enjoy school.
所以他有了压力 他并不享受小学生活
But then he experiences relief when the holidays come,
但他确实感受过轻松 在假期到来的时候
when they go on a family vacation or when the exams end and
在全家去度假 或者考试结束的时候
he can play with his friends without thinking of the next test.
在他可以不用担心考试和朋友玩的时候
He goes through school,not really liking it,
他经过了小学阶段 却不怎么喜欢
experiencing more series of reliefs rather than passion
他感受过轻松 却丝毫没有感受过
and love of learning which he did experience
在他还在幼儿园的时候感受过的那种
when he was in kindergarten,but no more.
对于学习的热情与喜爱
And he gets into his dream middle school-
他后来进入了梦想中的初中
the middle school that he was meant to go to all along.
那所他一直想要进入的初中
He makes it.
他做到了
And he feels wonderful and great and terrific for 2 weeks.
他只在前两周里感觉非常高兴
Because he now needs to start thinking about
因为他要开始考虑
the high school of his dreams.
他梦想中的高中了
Why? Because that high school
为什么 因为那所高中
is a feeder school for the top colleges in the country.
是进入全国最好的那些大学的垫脚石
And he really wants to get into one of those.
他也很想进入一间全国最好的大学
So he really struggles and works hard during,in middle school.
所以他在初中又很努力地学习
He doesn't really enjoy his work.
他并不怎么享受这样努力的过程
But he makes it,and he gets into his dream high school.
但是他成功了 他进入了梦想中的高中
And he is ecstatic.Happier than he had ever been before.
他很兴奋 从来没有这么高兴过
Because here he is- among the smartest kids in the country.
因为他已经是全国最出色的孩子中的一员
Very difficult to get into this school- but he makes it.
进这所高中不容易 但是他做到了
And there he starts to learn.
然后他又开始学习
He's happy for about a week and then the pressure mounts
他又只开心了一周 压力又来了
because it is a very competitive school
因为这所高中里面竞争非常激烈
and he has to join two varsity sports
他必须加入两个运动队
and three students organizations because he has to pad,
还有三个学生组织 因为他必须
to build his resume so that he gets into his dream college.
充实他的简历好让自己进入梦想中的大学
And he struggles,and it's not fun.
他过得很挣扎 一点意思也没有
But he says to himself,"this is just temporary.
但是他对自己说"这只是暂时的
It's only pain now,because later there will be gain-
痛苦是短暂的 等我进入了全国最优秀的
once I get into my top college." And he applies.
大学就会有回报的" 然后他付诸行动
And on April 2,there is an envelope that arrives.
在4月2号 一封信来了
And the envelope is large.And he opens it up and he gets in.
信的信封很大 他打开信知道自己成功了
And he is ecstatic,
他又感到非常地兴奋
happier even that he was when he got into his dream high school.
甚至比进入高中时还高兴
And he says,"now,finally,I can let go.
然后他说 "现在 我终于能放手
Now finally,I can relax.
好好地放松一下了
Because I've already made...I mean this top college.
因为我已经进了这间大学
And I'm set for life."
我的人生从此稳定下来了"
And he really enjoys the rest of senior year
接下来他十分享受高中的最后一年
and the holiday and then the freshman week comes.
还有假期以及进入大学的第一周
And he is ecstatic- Mr X.
他很兴奋 这位X先生
But then after that week,the pressure mounts again.
但是在第一周过去后 压力又出现了
Because very soon there are midterms.
因为很快就会到期中考试
And very soon there is competition.
而很快又会出现激烈的竞争
And everyone is working as hard as he did.
并且每个人都和他一样努力
And he has to work really hard
因此他也必须非常地努力
because he wants to get his dream job.
因为他想得到他的梦想中的工作
And then he gets his ideal internship during freshman summer
他在大一暑假的时候得到了理想的实习机会
and the pressure continues.
但是压力又继续出现了
There are reliefs; there are fun periods.
他感受过轻松 也感受过愉快的时光
And these are periods when the exams are just over
但是这些都是在考试结束以后
or when break is coming up.
或者假期即将到来之前
Or during break.
或者是在假期期间
But then again,the pressure mounts.
但是每次都一样 压力又出现了
He doesn't really understand why he's not happy
他自己也不明白为什么他不开心
because I mean this was where he really wanted to be,
因为这一切都是他想要的
he really really wanted to be- more than any other place.
他非常想要这些 多于别的一切
But he says "OK,once I get that job then I'll be set." Why?
他说"好的 只要我得到这份工作就好了" 为什么
Because that job will really get me into the top business school.
因为那份工作能让我进入最好的商学院
It will really differentiate me from all the other 1600 students
这能让我在一千六百个
who will graduate with me.
一同毕业的人中脱颖而出
So he works hard,still builds his resume.
所以他继续努力 继续充实他的简历
He's a member of 3 students organizations,president of two.
他是三个学生组织的成员 担任两个的部长
JV in two sports and varsity in one,plus taking five,
是两个大学运动预备队员 一个正式队员
and sometimes six courses in a semester.
还要加上每学期五门甚至六门课
Why? Because it's tough.It's competitive.
为什么 因为这很困难 竞争很激烈
And it's the survival of the fittest.And no pain,no gain.
这就是适者生存 不付出就没有收获
Senior year finally comes and there's pressure.
大学最后一年到来了 他又有压力了
But then he gets his job.He's happy.
但是他得到了那份工作 他很高兴
This is exactly what he wanted.
这就是他想要的
This is exactly what he envisioned.
这就是他所预想的
And now he's happy.
现在他很高兴
And then comes August 3,
然后8月3号到了
which is the date when he starts his actual work.
是他正式开始工作的第一天
And he goes to his work
他上班去
and everyone around him is graduated
他周围的所有人都是最高等学府的
from top universities,top places.
毕业生 都是最优秀学校的学生
He feels on top of the world.And he's happy for 2 weeks.
他觉得已经功成名就 却只高兴了两周
Because after 2 weeks,
因为在两周以后
he realizes there is a lot of pressure here,
他又感受到了非常大的压力
actually much more than it was in college.
比大学里面的压力还要大
And he can't have time for those long leisurely dinners
他没有时间再像大学里面一样在饭堂里
in the dinning hall.
悠闲地吃晚饭
He's working 80 t0 90 hours a week and not really enjoying it.
他每周工作八十到九十小时 一点也不享受
But he'll make it.He'll get there.
但是他会做到的 他会做得很好的
He'll do well,get a good recommendation for business school,
他会得到一封很好的进商学院的推荐信
and then after business school,
在从商学院毕业以后
get his real dream job and then he can enjoy himself.
找到一个真正的理想工作并享受生活
And he gets into his top business school choice
然后他真的进了最高的商业学院
and then he gets his top job.
也找到了他最好的工作
And in his job,as an associate,he's really happy.
工作上 作为一个员工 他很高兴
In fact he can't believe his good fortune.
事实上他甚至不敢相信自己的好运
He's making a lot of money.
他赚钱赚得很多
Those student debt looked so serious
那三年前看起来难以忍受的助学贷款
and over-bearing only 3 years ago and now are paid in an instant.
现在一下子就还清了
He feels good.
他感觉很棒
He has a nice apartment
他有了一间很不错的公寓
and he becomes an associate and he's ecstatic.
他成了员工 他很兴奋
He's happy,"I finally made it!"
他很高兴 "我终于做到了"
But a month goes by and the knot returns.
但是过了几个月 压力又回来了
Because he's only an associate.
因为他只是一个员工
He now really,really wants to make partner.
他非常非常想成为合伙人
But once he's partner,
但当他成为合伙人以后
once he got the so called "tenure" of the business world,
当他获得了"终身任期"以后
then he'll be all set.
他的生活就可以安顿下来了
And he works hard.He struggles.
他继续努力工作 奋力拼搏
He doesn't really enjoy his work.
他不怎么喜欢他的工作
But he says,"just another push.A little bit more pain.
只要再努力多一点 再忍受多一点痛苦
And then the real gain."
然后就会有真正的回报了
And after 5 years of pushing hard,he makes it.
在艰苦努力了五年以后 他又做到了
And he becomes a partner- in fact,
他成为了合伙人 事实上
one of the youngest partners in the history of the organization.
也是那个公司历史上最年轻的合伙人
And he's ecstatic.
他很兴奋
He takes a long break and comes back after the break,
他休了一个长假 然后回来工作
all motivated.
斗志满满
Because now he's owner,
因为他现在是所有者
part-owner of this great prestigious organization.
是这个著名的公司的所有者之一
And by now he has a family now already.And
现在他也已经成家了
he buys a huge house in one of the suburbs of the city,expensive
他买下了市郊的一座大房子 非常贵
But he bought it easily.And he buys a luxury car.
但是他轻易买下了 他也买了一辆豪华车
In fact he has a driver by now.And he feels on top of the world.
他还有了一个司机 他感觉真的功成名就了
He feels great for 3 months.And then the pressure returns.
他感觉良好地过了三个月 压力又来了
Because he's only a junior partner.
因为他只是一个初级合伙人
Can he make the senior partnership? Is it possible?
他能成为高级合伙人吗 这可能吗
Well,only if he works hard
好吧 只有努力工作才可能
because a few people make it that high up in the pyramid.
因为没多少人能爬到金字塔那么高的位置
It's getting tougher.But he'll make it.
越来越难了 但是他会成功的
So he struggles and he suffers,and it's not fun.
他挣扎着 忍受着 一点意思也没有
But he makes it.No pain,no gain.
但是他成功了 没有付出 就没有回报
And by this time,he's just bought another house in the Hamptons-
这一次 他在Hamptons区买了一栋房子
just for the holidays,for the breaks.
用来度假和休息
And there's another car- a bigger one,a faster one.
还有一辆新车 更大 也更快
And now he says,"I can finally,finally relax."
然后他说 我终于 终于 能够放松了
And he does relax.For 2 and a half months.
然后他开始放松自己 过了两个半月
And then the pressure returns.Because he's a senior partner.
压力又回来了 因为他只是个高级合伙人
But there is only one managing director.Only one.
但是常务董事只有一个
And to get that would be really tough.
想得到那个位置是非常困难的
But he's determined to do it.
但是他决心要当上常务董事
He's been a star; there's no reason to just stop now.
他一直是明星级人物 没理由止步不前
It's not fun for him.
这对他来说没什么乐趣可言
He doesn't spend that much time with people he loves,
他没有花多少时间和他爱的人一起
because he's constantly stressed; he has to prove himself.
而因为他心中的焦虑 他必须证明自己
And for 7 long years,
足足花了七年时间
while there is material affluence for those 7 years,
在这七年内 他在物质上已经很富足了
there is time poverty,time famine.
只是愈发地缺乏时间
But he continues to struggle and he makes it.
他不断地奋斗 最后终于成功了
The board makes an announcement.
董事会发表了任命声明
He's on the Wall Street Journal,front page news:
他登上了华尔街日报的头版新闻
Mr X is the new managing director of this incredible organization
X先生成为了这件传奇公司的常务董事
And his friends congratulate him.
他的朋友们祝贺他
He feels on top of the world.And he's happy.
他感觉万分自豪 他很快乐
But then the stress returns.
但是随后焦虑回来了
But then one day,one day he walks into his office,
有一天他走进办公室里
sits on his chair,puts his legs up on the table.
坐在椅子上 脚搭在桌子上
He's after all the Boss,the Man.
他已经成了老板 成了掌门人
He looks back and sees central park.
他回头就可以看见中央公园
Just beautiful there.
那景色实在太美了
He really is,not just metaphorically speaking-
他真的是 而不是修辞地说
he really is on top of the world.
他真的是站在了世界之巅
And then there is a knock on the door.
然后有人敲门了
He's surprised by the knock,
他被敲门声吓了一跳
because usually his secretary announces people-
因为一般来人了他的秘书会向他通报
they don't just knock on his door.
访客不会就这么过来敲门
He's after all,on top of the world.
毕竟他是站在世界之巅的人
So he walks down and opens the door.
于是他走过去开了门
And it's the chairman of the board.
来人是董事会主席
And she says hi to him.He says hi back.
他们俩互相打了个招呼
And she says,"you know,record earnings this year.
然后董事会主席说 "今年的盈利记录
Well done! Fantastic! You have done amazing,amazing work.
非常之棒 不可思议 您做得太好了
We are all so proud of you.So glad you are in your position.
我们都为您而骄傲 感谢您的存在
However,it's time to retire.You are 72 years old."
但是 您应该退休了 您已经72岁了"
This is the life of the rat racer- at best.
这就是逐利者的生活 最佳情况下
And again,this is a caricature.
当然这只是大概的描述
I've highlighted just certain points.
我只是着重描述了几个特殊的阶段
It's not as all or nothing.
这也不是要么全部要么没有
However,in essence,this is the life of the rat racer-
但是 总的来说 这就是逐利者的生活
about getting from point A to point B
只关注从A点到达B点
and then feeling relief for two weeks or a month.
然后轻松半个到一个月
And then getting...point B becomes point A.
然后...B点又变成了新的A点
And again,like the rat running around on and on and on and on.
然后 就像一直不断向上爬的老鼠
And you need to ask yourselves now- because not now then when?
你们必须现在就问自己 不现在问那还要等多久
You need to ask yourselves now,
你们必须现在就问自己
"what kind of life do I want for myself?"
"我到底想要什么样的生活"
I gave an example of business.
我给的是一个生意场上的例子
It applies as much to any other domain-
其实对于其他领域也一样
whether you are,want to become a medical doctor
不管你是想成为一个医生
and going on and feeling pressure to get into the best schools,
是因为能否上到最好的学校而有压力
the best department,the best internship,
是想要最好的公寓 最好的实习机会
the best,the highest position and on and on;
最想要好的 最高的职位等等
or whether you are working for a non profit organization;
或者你是打算为非盈利机构工作
or whether you are in academia; or a lawyer.
无论你是留在学术界 还是成为律师
It doesn't matter- just filling the blank of Mr X in which area.
都一样 都是在不同领域重复X先生的故事
It applies to any place.
这样的情况适用于任何地方
And the question is,"what kind of life do I want for myself?"
问题就是 "我们想要什么样的生活"
And remember the most important thing,
要记住其中最重要的
a person committed to excellence
一个追求卓越的人
does not give up on being ambitious.
不会放弃自己的雄心
However,a person committed to excellence
但是 一个追求卓越的人
does not also give up on the journey.
也不会放弃整个旅途
And as we'll talk about soon,
我们很快也会讲到
a person who is committed to excellence,
追求卓越的人
not only does he or she not give up on the journey
不仅仅不会放弃整个旅途
or rather on the outcome,
或者结果
they actually reach higher levels of performance.
他们常常会获得更高的成就
But we'll get to that soon.
我们很快就会讲到
A person committed to excellence
追求卓越的人
is not just about temporary relief,
并不只关注短时间的放松
but about lasting satisfaction.
还关注长久的满足
Yes,she has the ups and downs like we all do.
是的 生活中会有起起伏伏
However,also able to enjoy the journey day to day-
但是 也能够享受旅途中的每一天
the experience being the college,
在大学里的经历
the experience of having a lovely meal with my friends,
和朋友们美美地吃了一餐的经历
the experience of reading and being exposed to great writers,
阅读名家的作品的经历
to interesting classes,to nice extra curricular activities,
上有趣的课 参加有趣的课外活动的经历
and appreciating it,not taking it for granted,
并且重视这样的经历 而不是忽略它们
not seeing it as just incidental-
不是把这些看做普通的
just something that I need to get through
为了成功的最终目的
in order to get to where I really want to get to.
我必须经历的事情
Well,you may want to get...really want to get there,
你或许会非常渴望成功
but where you really are is here and now.
但是你所在的却是此时 此地
No other place.
不是别处
You know,I haven't met,maybe you have,
你们也知道 我从来没有 或许你们有
but I haven't met the perfect person.
我从来没有遇见过完美的人
I don't think that person exists.
我认为这样的人是不存在的
In other words,if there isn't a person,a perfect person,
换句话说 如果根本就不存在完美的人
for every person,there's inevitable failure.
那么对每个人来说 失败都是不可避免的
And a perfectionist who is obsessed with failure
为失败所困惑的完美主义者
just focuses on that,whereas the person committed to excellence,
只是专注于失败 而追求卓越的人
there is possibility of success every step of the way,
则会发现路途上每一步都有成功的机会
even in failure.
甚至在失败中也有这样的机会
A perfectionist very often wastes time-
完美主义者常常将时间浪费在
has to read every word,every...
必须读清楚每个字
You know,"i have to be dotted,every t crossed."
"我要做到最好 拿满分"
It's all or nothing.
要么全部要么没有
Either I hand in a perfect paper,
要么我交上去一份完美的论文
or I don't hand in a paper at all.
要么我就干脆不交论文
Either it's a straight A,or I'm a failure.
要么我就拿到A 要么我就一无是处
All or nothing.And sometimes,it's appropriate.
要么全部要么没有 有时候这是合适的
And that's what a person committed to excellence does-
有时候追求卓越的人也会持有这种态度
understands when,for example,
比如
if you are a surgeon,you want to have the perfect operation.
如果你是一个医生 你想做一场完美的手术
You don't want to say,"well,it's OK.
你可不会说 "好吧 没关系啊
I'm 80 percent right about where exactly to cut."
我切对了八成应该切的东西"
Yeah,there are places where you want the perfectionism.
没错 在有些场合你会需要完美主义
But in many other areas in our lives,it's not necessary.
但是在我们生活中的其他方面 都不必要
And it hurts us.A perfectionist is very often prone to disorders.
甚至会伤害我们 完美主义者往往倾向混乱
And I mean disorders of numerous times including,
我是指多方面的混乱
for example,eating disorder.
比如进食问题
So let me give you a personal example.
我来给你们提供一个个人的例子吧
So when I was playing squash,when I was playing full time,
在我还在打职业壁球的时候
I had to really take care of my diet- eat healthfully,eat well.
我必须控制我的食谱 要吃得健康吃得好
But there was a problem.
但还是产生了问题
There was a real challenge in my life.
我的生活中有一项重大挑战
And that challenge was my mother who is the perfect cook.
这挑战就是我的母亲个完美的大厨
And her cakes are outstanding.
她做的的蛋糕尤其诱人
So here is the common scenario that
于是就有了这样的我在长大的时候
I encountered growing up- tough childhood:
常常遇到的状况 痛苦的童年
I would come home after the squash practice,
我在壁球训练过后回家
open the fridge,starving.
饿得要命地打开冰箱
And there was a large piece of cake.
然后那里面有一大块蛋糕
Not a whole cake,but you know a quarter cake,
不是一整个 但差不多四分之一个
very large,so inviting.So alluring.
非常大的一块 实在是非常诱人
And I know from past experiences it's so delicious.
我根据以往的经验知道 这很好吃
I look at it.And then I close the fridge.
我看着这块蛋糕 然后关上了冰箱门
Because I can't have it.
因为我不能吃
I'm in middle of training for an important tournament.
当时我正在在为一个重要的巡回赛训练
But three minutes later,
但是在三分钟以后
I go to the fridge again,just to make sure it's still there.
我回到冰箱那看蛋糕还在不在
Why? Those of you who know my brother understand why.
为什么 你们中认识我兄弟的都明白
My brother is much bigger than I am.
我兄弟块头比我大多了
And he likes my mom's cooking no less than I do.
他对我母亲的厨艺的喜爱一点不在我之下
So I was just making sure that it was still there.
所以我去确定蛋糕还在那
And it was.
确实还在
And then 10 minutes later,I had to go back because my brother
再过了十分钟 我必须再去检查一遍
had just disappeared from my eyes a few minutes.
因为我兄弟在我视线内消失了几分钟
I thought he went to the fridge.
我以为他到冰箱那去了
So I opened the fridge again and it was still there.
所以我又打开了冰箱一次 蛋糕还在
So I was relieved.
然后我感到一阵轻松
And about 5 minutes later I had to go back to the fridge.
大约五分钟以后我又回到冰箱那里
I opened the door and two minutes later,there was no cake.
我打开冰箱门 两分钟以后蛋糕就不见了
All or nothing.Either I don't touch it,or I devour it.
要么全部要么没有 要么我不碰要么我吃完
This is the schema that a perfectionist has.
这就是完美主义者持有的基模
It's not "OK,let me have a slice of it." It's nothing or all.
不会说"好吧 我就吃一块" 要么不吃要么吃完
And this is the schema that perfectionists have:
所以这就是完美主义者的基模
either I'm a supermodel or I'm overweight.
我要么成为超级模特 要么超重
All or nothing.And it's destructive.
要么全部要么没有 这是很有破坏力的
It hurts so much on so many levels.
这会对我们产生各个层次的严重伤害
As opposed to the healthy approach.
相对于健康的方式而言
OK,so I'll have a slice.So I'll have a little bit.
好的 我就吃一小块
OK,so I gained a couple of pounds- big deal?! I'm human.
好的 我重了几磅 这算大事吗 我是人
I'm not a machine.I'm not a Barbie.Or Ken.(Laugh)
我不是机器 也不是芭比娃娃 更不是Ken
I caught myself there.
我说错话了
Hurts self-esteem.Why? Because...
这很伤自尊 为什么 因为
Nathaniel Branden who writes about self-esteem-
Nathaniel Branden写过很多关于自尊的文字
we'll talk a lot about him in that lecture 3 weeks from now.
我们在未来三周内将会更多地讲到他
The first pillar of self-esteem is self-acceptance.
自尊的第一个基础就是自我接受
And remember a perfectionist does not accept him/herself.
要记得完美主义者是不接受自我的
Second,the reason why it hurts self-esteem- remember,
第二个伤害自尊的原因是
there is constant,inevitable failure for a perfectionist
完美主义者总会遇到长期且不可避免的失败
because there is no perfect person.And
因为根本就没有完美的人
if I constantly fail or constantly perceive myself as a failure,
而如果我一直失败或者视自己为失败者
am I going to have high self-esteem? Of course not.
那我还会有较高的自尊心吗 当然不会
It also hurts self-esteem because a perfectionist
另一个完美主义者容易自尊心受伤的原因
is less likely to try,less like to put him/herself on the line.
是他们更不愿意去尝试
And the price that I pay for that
而如果我不愿意尝试的话 其后果就是
when I don't try is lower level of self-esteem.
更加低的自尊心
Remember self-perception theory.
还记得自我知觉理论吗
Versus on-going,continuous improvement.
相对的是持续的自我提升
Not a straight line,but a spiral that goes up and up.
不是一条直线直上的 而是旋转向上的
Perfectionism harms relationships.
完美主义伤害人际关系
Again,I just look back and I,you know from this perspective,
回想过去 我从这个角度来说
it's hard for me to fathom the kind of mistakes
我很难捉摸 我基于完美主义
that I have made in relationships based on perfectionism.
在人际关系中所犯的错误的类型
Why? First of all,defensiveness.
为什么 第一 自卫性
It is very difficult to form intimacy with some one
如果我一直是处于自卫性的位置
when I'm constantly on the defensive,when I can't accept
如果我不能接受或者处理批评
or do something at the very least with criticisms.
那我就很难和别人形成亲密的关系
What kind of intimacy is possible there?
这样的情况下怎么可能建立亲密关系呢
The other reason why it harms relationships
另一个完美主义伤害人际关系的原因是
is that very often,we mirror...
我们经常
Our approach to the world mirrors our approach toward ourselves.
我们对世界的看法和对自己的看法一样
So if I'm a perfectionist and expect perfectionism-
如果我是完美主义者那我期望的就是完美
a straight line for myself,I would expect the same from others,
对我来说是一条直线 对他人亦是如此
whether it's from my partner,
不论是对于我的伴侣
whether it's later on my children or friends.
还是对我的孩子和朋友
And now as we...
现在我们...
I think- I establish before- there is no perfect person.
我以前也说过了 没有完美的人
Now it may seem perfect when we first meet.
我们第一次见面的时候可能感觉是完美的
And during the honeymoon phase,it is perfect.
在度蜜月的时候 也是完美的
He or she is perfect.
他或她是完美的
But beyond that,suddenly,we begin to identify flaws.Hey,
但是突然 我们开始发现对方的缺点了
that's not the person I thought I got together with initially.
那不是我一开始以为可以在一起的那人
Yes,of course it's not,if what I expect is Barbie or Ken.
当然 如果我期待的是芭比娃娃或Ken的话
Straight line.But it's a human being.
完美的 但是对方可是人
And if I expect perfectionism from the other,
如果我从对方身上期待的是完美
I will inevitably be disappointed.
我肯定会失望的
And that leads to frustration,
这也会引起沮丧
lacks of acceptance toward the partner,
对自己的伴侣不认可
and very often,usually harms the relationship.
也常常会伤害到人与人之间的关系
Versus on-going growth of the relationship,
相对于持续成长的关系来说
as we'll talk about when we talk about relationships.
这是我们会在谈论人际关系的时候谈论到的
The ideal relationship
理想的人际关系
is not a relationship that is devoid of failure,
不是一个没有失败
that is devoid of disagreements.
没有不和的关系
The ideal relationship is one where there's mostly good stuff,
理想的人际关系在包含众多积极因素同时
but there's also disagreements,disappointments,fights.
也会包含不和 失望和争吵
That's actually healthy.
那才是健康的人际关系
It helps the relationship become stronger over time.
这让人际关系随时间变得更加稳固
The issue is of degree.
关键是其中的度
How much positive versus negative
你在人际关系中包含的
do you have in the relationship?
积极因素与消极因素各是多少
The issue is not having only positives and no negatives.
这里的关键不是只有积极而没有消极的因素
That's not a healthy relationship.
这样的关系是不健康的
That's a relationship
这样的关系
with a lot of suppression and repression at best.
有过多的抑制与压抑
Perfectionism leads to anxiety,leads to stress.
完美主义会导致焦虑和压力
There is always a fear of failure.
总会有对于失败的恐惧
Versus excitement.
而不是兴奋
What Peter Senge called "creative tension".
这就是Peter Senge所说的"创造性张力"
But what about performance?
但是表现如何
What about the "no pain,no gain" mantra
那句已经镌刻在我们心中的
that's drilled into our mind constantly?
"没有付出就没有收获"的真言呢
I mean we know self-evident that
我是说我们很清楚地都知道
we need to work hard in order to succeed.
我们必须要努力才能成功
So shouldn't I be a perfectionist?
那难道我不应成为完美主义者吗
And one of the main reasons why people don't give up the schema
而人们不愿放弃这种方式的一个原因是
is because they think this is the fastest way,
他们认为这是最快的方法
most efficient way to success.
是最为有效的通往成功的方法
But it turns out that it's not the case,
但是最后事情往往都不是那样的
that actually the person committed to excellence
长久来看 追求卓越的人往往
is more successful in the long run.
会取得更好的成就
And there is a lot of research that illustrates this.
在这方面有很多研究进行了阐释
Let me share some of it.Some of the reasons.
我来举出一些成果 一些原因
Now,less pain,more gain.
现在说说少一点付出 多一点收获
First of all,in the ultimate currency,
首先 以终极货币的形式
the most important currency of happiness.
用幸福来进行衡量
People committed to excellence
追求卓越的人
as opposed to perfectionists are happier.
远比完美主义者要快乐
So that's wonderful and that's great.
这很好 也很棒
But it's not just in the ultimate currency,
但也不仅仅是在终极货币价值方面
it's also in the hard currency,
在硬通货等物质方面也是同样的
whether it's success at work,whether it's success for athletes,
不管是工作上的成功 还是体育上的成功
whether it's success in relationships.
还是处理人际关系上的成功
Various reasons.
为什么 其中有很多原因
First of all,person committed to excellence
首先 追求卓越的人
enjoys much more sustainable approach to growth.
享受更加可持续的成长
Remember,
记住了
the analogy that I use from environmentalism- sustainable growth.
这个我从环保方面引用的词 可持续增长
It's not about having a sterile environment.
不是要创造一个贫瘠的环境
It's not about going back to the days of
不是关于回到以狩猎与采集为
when we lived as hunters and gathers in caves.
主要生活方式的时代去的
It is living in accordance of modern life.
是关于以现代生活方式生活
It is enjoying modernity and progress,but at the same time,
是关于享受进步与现代性 与此同时
not taking too much out of the environment
不从环境中索取过多
so that it can sustain itself.
让发展得以持续下去
The same on the individual level.
放到个人层面上也是一样的
A perfectionist does not enjoy sustainable approach to growth.
完美主义者不会享受持续性的成长
Because there are no places for recovery,no places for deviation
因为他们不允许休整和偏离
Everything is static like a machine.
所有东西都是不变的 如同一台机器
As opposed to a person committed to excellence:
至于追求卓越的人
there are deviations,there are breaks,there are recoveries.
有所偏离 有所中断 也有休整
Much more sustainable.Versus all or nothing.I got injured.
相比起来更加可持续 如果我受伤了
My squash career ended because it was all or nothing.
我的壁球生涯就结束了 因为要么全部要么没有
Either I don't train at all
要么我就完全不训练
or I train like Jansher Khan,the world champion.
要么我就像世界冠军Jansher Khan那样训练
Also intrinsic motivation
同时追求卓越的人所拥有的
is much higher for people committed to excellence.
固有动力也比完美主义者高很多
And when we have intrinsic motivation,
当我们有固有动力的时候
we are much more likely to sustain effort
我们就能更好地在一段时间内持续地
over a long period of time,
付出努力
and if all the motivation is intrinsic.
如果所有的动力都是固有不会减退的
Comes to getting to that next stage.
那就能上升到另一个层次
Getting those accolades.Getting that raise and so on.
获得嘉奖 或者能得到升迁
Winston Churchill said that perfectionism spells paralysis.
丘吉尔说完美主义让人瘫痪
When we are so obsessed with failure,
当我们被失败所困扰的时候
we are much less likely to act.
我们就更不会付诸行动
One of the primary causes of procrastination is perfectionism-
完美主义是事情耽搁的最主要原因之一
the incapacitating fear of failure.
对失败的失能性畏惧
Cause if we don't act,we don't fail.
因为只要我们不行动 我们就不会失败
Self-esteem as I mentioned earlier
就如同我之前说的 追求卓越的人的自尊
is much higher for a person committed to excellence.
相比起来更高
And as Nathaniel Branden said,self concept is destiny;
而且如Nathaniel Branden所说 自我知觉
beliefs become self-fulfilling prophecies.
是终点 而信念变成自我实现预言
If I believe in myself,if I think I can succeed,
如果我相信我自己 如果我认为我能成功
if I have the track record to show that
如果我的过去有跌倒之后
I get up after falling down,
又爬起来的经历
I'm much more likely to succeed over time.
那我就更可能成功
Did I mention this before? Oh.OK.Good.
我以前讲过这个吗 好的
Because it is important.There is no other way to succeed.
因为这很重要 要成功没有别的方式
You are at "the Luck Factor",
你们读到了"运气的因素"
the fantastic work by Wiseman,UK professor.
英国的Wiseman教授极为优秀的作品
And what he talks about,one of the causes of having more luck
他所说的是 比别人有更多运气的原因
in our lives seems like a mystical thing,
似乎是一件很神秘的事情
but actually can be shown scientifically.
但其实也是可以用科学方法解释的
One of the ways of having more luck
其中一个有更好运气的方法
in our lives is to try new things,little things,
便是尝试新事情 小事情
even when you walk back to your dining hall after class.
即使是你课后去食堂的路上
Take a slightly different path,as opposed to the path
找一条和你每天所走的那条路
that has already been taken by you every single day.
有些许不同的路线
And he says these little changes in our lives,
而她说 这些小事就可以改变我们的生活
these slight deviations from a straight narrow actually
这些小小的对于直线方式的偏离实际上
lead to higher levels of luck,
能带来更多的幸运
because we begin to see things that we haven't seen before.
因为我们开始看见以前没见过的东西
Perfectionist- one way;
完美主义者 只有一条路
no deviations,no improvisation,no spontaneity.
没有偏离 没有进步 没有自发性
This very often prevents us from being "luckier".
这些时常都让我们变得不那么"幸运"
Creativity- Simonton: the most successful,
说到创造力 Simonton说 那些历史上
the most creative scientist and artist throughout the history
最成功 最有创造力的科学家和艺术家
are ones that fail the most.
都是那些失败得最多的
They were not perfectionists.
他们都不是完美主义者
They were committed to excellence- extremely ambitious,
他们都追求卓越 非常有雄心
understanding that there's no other way to succeed.
都明白要成功没有别的方法
John Updike,highly creative author,
John Updike 一位非常有创造力的作家
says "perfectionism is the enemy of creativity."
说过"完美主义是创造力的敌人"
And we'll talk about another author
我们会谈到另一个作家
who has very good advice for us of
他对于我们如何克服这种完美主义
how to overcome this perfectionism,Samuel Coleridge.
有非常好的建议 他叫Samuel Coleridge
The 80/20 rule.
80/20规则
This rule- understanding this rule
这条规则 了解这条规则并将其应用在
as it applies to time management changed my Harvard experience.
时间管理上改变了我在哈佛的学习经历
So what is the Pareto principle?
那帕累托法则是什么呢
Pareto was an Italian economist about 100 years ago.
帕累托是100年前的意大利经济学家
And he came up with this principle
他得出了这样的法则
which he named the Pareto principle.
并将其命名为帕累托法则
And the principle says that in most societies,
这法则表示 在大多数社会中
20 percent of the people own about 80 percent of the wealth.
百分之二十的人拥有百分之八十的财富
They applied this principle to organizations as well,
他们也将这条法则应用于商业组织
where 20 percent of your clients
那就是你百分之二十的客户
generate 80 percent of your income.
给你带来了百分之八十的收入
And this has been applied to many areas in economics.
这也被用于经济学的许多领域
And more recently,to time management.
而到最近 被用于时间管理方面
For example,in 20 percent of our time,
比如说 在我们百分之二十的时间里
we can get 80 percent of our work done.
我们可以完成百分之八十的工作
And when I understood this,
而当我明白这一点的时候
it changed my approach toward my academics.
它改变了我对学术的态度
Why? Because I realized that
为什么 因为我意识到
well I didn't need to read 100 percent of the material.
我不必将那些材料完全读完
Again,don't quote me on this.
再说一遍 这点别学我
I didn't need to make sure that every t's crossed
我交论文前不必确认每一个t都写好了
and every i's dotted when I handed in the paper.
也不必确认每一个i上面都点了点
And I started to follow much more the pleasure principle
我开始遵循更多的愉悦原则 或者说
or the happiness principle and I said,
快乐原则 于是我说
"OK,this is something that I really cared about."
"好的 这才是我感兴趣的东西"
For example,I don't know if this class is still offered now.
比如说 我不知道这门课还有没有
Lit and Arts C14 "Heroes".
文学与艺术学院课程 C14 "英雄"
Still offered now? One of my favorite classes,as an undergrad.
还能报名吗 这是我本科时候最喜欢的课程
And it's not a very difficult class.
而且这课程还不算太难
I could do very well without putting too much in it.
我完全可以不怎么努力也得好成绩
But I spent a 50 hours on final paper.
但是我在这科的期末论文上花了50个小时
Because I wrote about a topic that I really really cared about.
因为我写的主题是我非常关心的
And I didn't get an A for it,which didn't make any sense to me.
但是我没有得A 对我来说毫无道理
But I still put in so much work in it.
但我仍然在上面下了大工夫
Because it was fun,whereas other classes that I enjoyed less,
因为这实在是太有意思了 至于其它课程
I put in what I needed in order to get what I thought was enough.
我只投入了能让我得到足够成绩的时间
Not all or nothing.
不是要么全部要么没有
Either I study and get a straight A,or I don't study at all.
不会说要么我就得A 要么我就不学习
Another class-
另一门课
I don't know if it's still taught- Lit and Arts again,
我不知道这门课还有没有 还是文学与艺术
"Fairy Tales"? With Maria Tatar? She teaches another class now.
Maria Tatar教的"神话故事" 她现在上别的课了
I had a crush on her when I was an undergrad.
我本科时看见她第一眼就爱上了她
I can't believe that I just said it loud.(Laugh)
我真不敢相信我就这么说出来了
So yeah,she said no.Um no I didn't ask her.I didn't.
那么 她拒绝了 其实我没有问她
So also in that class- not a very difficult class.
也是在那门课上 不算太难的课
A very enjoyable class on many levels.
在许多层次上来说非常享受的课
And again,putting a lot of work into a paper that
又一次 我花了许多时间在这篇
there by the way ultimately began the to...
最终成为一篇以自尊为主题的
became the topic of my dissertation on self-esteem.
专题论文之上
So again,asking what is most important for me?
所以再一次问自己到底什么才是重要的
What do I really care about as opposed to saying all or nothing.
除了要么没有要么全部外 我还在乎什么
Now my grades did go down slightly as a result.
我的成绩确实下降了一点点
But really very little.
但是只是很少一点点
Because I was employing that 20/80 rule.
因为我在应用这条20/80法则
20 percent of focus on what's important
将百分之二十的注意力放到重要的东西上
and got the 80 percent of the work done.
然后把百分之八十的工作做好
And I became so much more successful
而我在学术的其它领域
in other areas of my academic career,
却获得了更多的成功
because I had more time to play squash
因为我有了更多的时间来打壁球
and enjoy my squash practice.
来享受壁球练习
I had more time for socializing,
我有了更多时间来和别人交流
for sitting in Law House and having a two and a half hour dinner,
有时间去坐在法学院里吃一次五点开始的
starting at 5 pm.
持续两个半小时的晚餐
Just based on that.
就是在这样的基础上实现的
Another application of the 80/20 rule:
另一个对于80/20的应用
all of us have different time during the day
我们每人在一天中都有不同的
when we are most productive.
最有工作效率的时间
In fact,in 20 percent of the day,we get 80 percent,
实际上 在一天中百分之二十的时间内
potentially,80 percent of our work done,
我们完成了百分之八十的工作
depending whether we are morning people or night people.
这取决于我们是早起的鸟还是夜猫子
There are people who get up in the morning at you know 6,7 am
有的人早上6点或7点就起来了
and they are ready to go.
然后他们立刻就可以工作了
That's me.I get up early.Very easy for me.
我也是这样的 我很早起床 对我很简单
I just go straight to my computer or to change a diaper.
我可以直接开电脑工作或去给孩子换尿布
Very early in the morning.First thing.No problem.
很早的早上 直接去工作 没问题
At night,by 9,10 pm,complete zombie.
但是到了晚上9点10点 就完全不行了
And there are people who are the opposite-
有人却是截然相反的
can stay up till 2,3,4 am in the morning,
他们可以熬夜到凌晨2点 3点 4点
and that's when they are the freshest.
那才是他们最有干劲的时候
By the way,it has to do with our internal biorhythm,
这和我们内在的生物节奏有关
internal circadian rhythms.
和我们的生理节奏有关
Because there are some people for whom-
因为有人
no one is exactly or very few people are exactly 24 hours rhythms
基本上没有人的周期是正好24小时的
We are usually either somewhere between 23 and 25.
大多数人都是23到25小时之间
So for people whose circadian rhythm is 23 hours,
对于周期是23小时的人来说
they get very tired at night.
他们到了晚上就会非常疲劳
But then they wake up very fresh in the morning.
但是他们早上却会精神抖擞地起来
Or people who are closer to 25
那些周期是25小时的人
need that extra sleep in the morning.
早上需要多睡一会
And it's for those people that I have this class at 11:30.
就是因为那些人我才将这课调到11点半
I know it's early but thank you for making the effort.
我知道是很早但是感谢你们的到来
When I got to college,most students were studying late at night.
我上大学的时候 大多数人都学到很晚
My roommates were studying late at night,starting at about 10
我的室友就学到很晚 从晚上10点开始
and going to you know midnight or 2 am in the morning.
然后学到12点甚至凌晨2点
And that's when they are most productive.I wasn't.
这才是他们最有效率的时候 可我不是
And I would get up in the morning
我宁愿早上早点起来
and I was tired,exhausted,couldn't really focus at night.
我在晚上会很累 根本无法集中精神
And when I heard about this productive hour,I changed my day.
我听说了这样的效率时段后 我改变了作息
And I went to sleep early.
我早早睡觉
So when my roommates started to study,I actually went to bed,
在我的室友开始学习的时候 我上床睡觉
and got up really early when my roommates were still asleep
然后在我的室友还在睡的时候起床
and got my work done early in the morning,
然后在早上早早地把工作完成
and then went to my 11 am class after I got my work done.
做完以后去上11点的课
And in 3 hours in the morning,
在早上的那3个小时内
I got much more done- more productive,more creative,
我完成了更多东西 更有效率更有创造性
much better retention than I did late at the night.
比我在晚上熬夜有效率得多了
These two things as I mentioned earlier
我刚才说到的那两样东西
really changed my experience here-
真的改变了我在这里的经历
getting so much more in far less time.
在更短的时间内学到更多
Not the perfectionist approach,the pursuing excellence approach.
不是完美主义的方式 是追求卓越的方式
You read about "flow"-
大家都了解过"流动"了
Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi who talks about flow
Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi谈论过流动
is being peak experience we enjoy the most and peak performance-
是我们最良好的感受 最出色的表现
we perform at our best,defying the "no pain,no gain" formula.
也就是"没有付出就没有收获"
And when do we experience flow?
我们什么时候感受到流动
Not when we experience the high levels of anxiety
我们焦虑的时候感受不到
as the perfectionist often does,not when we are bored,
就如完美主义者那样 我们无聊时感受不到
but when it's the optimum levels of arousal,when we are excited.
只有我们乐观愉快 兴奋的时候感受得到
The person committed to excellence
追求卓越的人
is much more likely to experience the flow
更容易感觉到流动
than the person who is constantly afraid of failure,
而那些一直畏惧失败的人
constantly obsessed with failure,
一直为失败所困扰的人
constantly thinking about what if I fail.
一直在设想如果我失败了怎么办的人
Let me talk a little bit about the sources of the perfectionism.
我来谈谈完美主义的根源吧
Because if we understand that,as I mentioned last time,
因为一旦我们明白 就如我上次说的
if we understand where it comes from,
一旦我们明白它是怎么来的
we are much more likely to be able to get over it.
我们就更能克服它
So some of these sources of perfectionism.
完美主义的根源
The first one,the most important one is conditioning.
第一个 最重要的因素就是社会影响
I mean we are not born perfectionist.
我们都不是天生的完美主义者
Children as you saw in the video- they are,as you know,
你们在录影带中看到的孩子 他们天生
born actually enjoying the learning process much more than we do.
比我们更能享受学习的过程
When we are afraid of failing,they fall and they get up again.
我们畏惧失败 他们却不断跌掉了又爬起
So it's through conditioning that
所以是社会的影响导致了
we learn to be afraid of failure,specifically,
我们对于失败的畏惧 确切地说
the schema that we internalize
是这样一种在我们心中烙下的
that's being reinforced constantly from almost the time
并且几乎从出生开始就不断被加深的基模
when we were born- that what matters is the destination.
那就是 成果才是真正重要的
When we get to a certain destination
当我们得到了某个成果的时候
such as learning how to walk- well done!
比如学会走路 做得好
Such as getting A at the end of my first grade- terrific!
在我第一年期末的时候得了A 真不错
Gold star! It's the destination that's rewarded.
只有我们的成果受到了奖励
And after a while,we begin to internalize this schema
过了没多久 我们就开始内化这种基模
and we begin to believe that we accept it
并且我们也开始相信我们接受它
when we achieve a certain completion
当我们达成了某种成就的时候
and goes on throughout our lives.
这样的事在我们的生活中一直延续着
I mean when do we get a bonus?
我们什么时候会得到奖金
On April 3? No,we get it on December 31!
在4月3号吗 当然不是 是在12月31号
Or just before Christmas at the end of the year.
或者说是圣诞节之前 年末
This was a good productive year.Well done.
今年大家都干得不错 很好
When do we get the grades,
我们什么时候会得到分数
the pats on the back if we did work well?
还被别人轻拍后背表示做得不错
At the end of the semester.
是在学期末
Or after an exam when we have completed something.
或是在考试后 我们完成了某些事的时候
Not during the journey.
不会在旅途中得到
In other words,the journey goes unrewarded.
换句话说 整个旅途都没有受到奖励
And we begin to perceive it as inconsequential,
于是我们也就开始认为它是无关的
not important,just a means toward an end.
是不重要的 只是到达终点的一种方式
Very few teachers,parents,organizations,
只有非常少的教师 家长 组织
schools reward the journey- the enjoyment of the journey.
还有学校会奖励旅途 奖励旅途中的愉快
And of course,very few reward,lo and behold,failure,
当然 也有很少的人会奖励失败
which is an inevitable part of every journey
可这是旅途中不可避免的
so that we learn no good- this is no good-
所以我们觉得这不好 这一点也不好
we must have as much as possible a straight line.
我们必须尽可能地追求直线
A straight schema.
一种直接的基模
And we pay a price for it when we internalize it.
我们内化它的时候也付出了代价
And this is the kind of social environment that we are born into,
这就是我们出生所在的社会环境
that we are raised in,
我们成长所在的社会环境
and the social environment that is very difficult to change.
而这样的社会环境很难以改变
I mean I know- I have little kids at home.
我也知道 我家里也有孩子
It is so difficult to change it
这太难以改变了
because very often I'm inclined to say to focus
因为我自己也时常对孩子说并且专注于
from early on the day "Oh Shirell just learned how to walk!
"Shirell学会走路了
Well done! You know you just walk"
做得好 你学会走路了"
as opposed to rewarding the effort as we'll talk about
而不是奖励其中所付出的努力
in a minute and rewarding the hard work and
我们等会会讲到 奖励付出的努力
rewarding even the failure,the trying,the coping,the process.
甚至奖励失败 应对与整个过程
Very difficult.
非常难
And that's connected,of course,to the permission to be human.
这当然也和准许为人有联系
The permission for the constraint of view of the human nature,
准许看到人类本性的限制
as opposed to the idealized,disconnected,
而不是理想化 孤立地
detached of view of what life can look like.
分离地看待生活
Because it can't.
因为这不可能
Instead of permission to be human,there's pressure to be perfect
如果不是准许为人 而是要求完美的话
It's constant.It's on-going.
压力是持久存在的
It's in the media.It's in the workplace.
存在于媒体中 存在于工作中
It's in our educational institutions.
存在于教育机构中
It's everywhere.And we pay a price for it.
这无处不在 我们也为之付出了代价
Now let me give you some examples.
现在 我来给你们看几个例子
Before I give this example,just a quick introduction.
在那前先给你们介绍一下
As you know,academics don't make that much money.
你们都知道 学术研究赚不了多少钱
When people go into academia,it's usually not for the money.
进入学术圈的人 大多都不是为了钱
So many academics,
有很多学者
myself being known no exception have to supplement their income.
我也不例外 必须额外赚取收入
So I supplement my income-
我也有额外的收入
and I want to share with you something that I do on the side.
而我希望和你们分享一下我额外做的事
(Laugh) Yeah.My glasses are just to hide the abs.Yeah.
我的眼镜掩饰了我有腹肌的事实
So I mean,is he real?
那么 他是真实的吗
Is anyone in this room who looks like this?
这间房间里有谁是长这样的吗
Yeah,didn't mean for you to answer that question.
我也没指望你们来回答
But I mean is this real? Well,partially.
但我的意思是 他是真实的吗 部分真实的
A lot of it is photoshoped.
这照片修过不少地方
But yeah,there are some people who look like this.
但是没错 确实有人长是这样的
But what do we see in the magazines?
但是我们在杂志会看到什么
I mean if you go to the magazine store.
我是说 如果你们进一家杂志店里面去
You know the magazines these are the kind of people
你们也知道这种杂志的 这些就是
who are on the cover.
封面上的人物
Perfect.Perfect beings.
十分完美 完美的存在
Even more so-
甚至更加地
you know so we have our Kens- even more so with the Barbies.
我们的Ken还有芭比娃娃都更加完美
I just do a lot of work on Google image.So look at this.
我在谷歌图片上找了好久 来看看吧
"The Progress of Science".
"科学的进步"
"Some Examples of Recent Art".
"近代艺术的范例"
Just like Cosmo today,right? Well,so look at this.
就像今天的Cosmo杂志一样 不是么 看这个
"Sex Goddess Secrets".
"性爱女神的秘密"
I mean,it's not even "Sex HUMAN Secrets"!
我是说 这甚至不是"性爱人类的秘密"
That's not good enough!
那还不够好
Look at these standards that are set for ourselves!
看看我们为自己定下的这些标准吧
How am I ever going to match that! Or here- oh I didn't see that.
我怎么才能变成那样 这里 我没看到
"The Naughty Thing 30%..." I should read that.(Laugh)
"百分之三十的..."我应该好好读一读
But that's not what I want to point to.
但这不是我想指的
I actually wanted to point to this- "How to Get Ahead Fast".
其实我想指这个"如何快速进步"
As fast as you can,right? There is no time.Or this- "Never".
要多快有多快 对吧 时间不多
"Never Have a Zit Again".I mean,I still have zits.I'm 37.
"永远不长痘痘"我都37岁了还有痘痘
What do...How do they do that?! Again,unrealistic models.
他们怎么做到的 又是不现实的模型
You know in 1997 when I was living in Singapore,
1997年我还在新加坡住的时候
I wanted to bring Nathaniel Branden to Singapore.
我想带Nathaniel Branden去新加坡
Again,he is considered the leading person on self-esteem.
他被认为是自尊研究的领头人
His wife,Devers Branden has done a lot of work
他的妻子Devers Branden也在自尊
in the areas of self-esteem and personal growth.
与自我成长方面花了很多功夫
So I wanted to bring them both.
所以我希望能让他们来新加坡
So I brought them to consult for the organization
所以我请他们来为我工作的公司
where I was working.
做咨询
And I was looking for other ways
我在寻找其他途径
because it was very expensive for other ways of funding that trip
因为其他途径所要筹集的经费比较多
And a close friend of mine,
而我的一个好朋友
Pat Lee was working at the time with the Body Shop.
Pat Lee那时在为美体小铺工作
And she said,"you know,this is perfect.
她说"这实在是太好了
Because the Body Shop this year and Anita Roddick
因为美体小铺还有Anita Roddick
whom I mentioned earlier is interested in self-esteem for women.
我之前提过她 对于女性自尊也很感兴趣
So why don't we do a project with Devers and Nathaniel
那为什么我们不能让Devers和Nathaniel
and the Body Shop joint venture
还有美体小铺联合起来
and have self-esteem for women in Singapore?"
在新加坡搞一次关于女性自尊的活动呢
I thought it was a great idea.
我认为这主意非常不错
I actually met with Anita Roddick.
我和Anita Roddick见了面
And we co-sponsored Nathaniel Branden-
然后我们共同赞助了Nathaniel Branden
it was a highly successful event.
后来这次活动非常成功
We had 700 seats; over 1000 people came.
本来有700个座位 可来了1000多人
We had to have plasma outside.
我们得在场外放置等离子大屏幕
And in addition,it made a huge stir
还有 这次活动对很多人产生了激励
and really started a movement or a mini movement
并激发了一场运动 或者说是小规模运动
in Singapore- self-esteem for women.
在新加坡的 女性自尊的运动
As a result,
作为结果
Nathaniel Branden wrote a book,called "Self-esteem For Women".
Nathaniel Branden写了本书 叫"女性的自尊"
Cause he's blown away with the fascinating stories
因为他被我们在研讨会上所讲述的
that were told in the seminar and so on.
那些故事给深深吸引了
Anyway,but Anita Roddick has done a lot of work
不管怎么说 Anita Roddick在女性和自尊方面
for women and self-esteem.
做了不少工作
And one of the projects- she did that in 1997-
其中一个项目 她在1997年策划的
I think you were,most of you were too young to be aware of it,
我觉得你们大多都太年轻了 可能不知道
but it was on all Body Shop stores was one
但是所有美体小铺的分店都有一个
that she based on a doll called Ruby,the alternative to Barbie.
叫做Ruby的洋娃娃 用来取代芭比娃娃
And here is what the campaign looked like.
然后那次活动是这样的
Whoops! Sorry.
抱歉
"There are 3 billion women who don't look like supermodels
"有三十亿女人长得不像超级模特
and only 8 who do."
只有8个才像"
Or "Hey media,
或者"媒体们
Where we come from cultural and physical diversity is the norm.
在我们家乡 文化与生理的多样才是标准
It's called Planet earth."
那里就是地球"
Very effective campaign.And so important.
这次活动非常成功 也很重要
Because what of the models that
因为我们今天文化中的
we have today in our culture- all or nothing.
模型就是这样的 要么全部要么没有
I mean,this picture by the way came together.
这些照片是一同被找到的
I didn't put them together.
我没把它们特意放在一起
Either you binge,or the alternative.
要么你大吃大喝 要么就不吃不喝
Or what do we get in the movies?
我们从电影中得到了什么
I mean who possibly can live up to the standards of Top Gun?
谁能达到《壮志凌云》里面的标准
Tom Cruise and Kelly McGillis.
汤姆克鲁斯和凯莉麦吉利斯
The perfect love that they had there,
他们拥有的那种完美的爱情
but this is the model that we had-
但这是我们所有的模型
and I'll talk about it when I talk about relationships.
等我们谈到恋爱关系的时候会讲到
Who possibly can sustain even for "9 1/2 Weeks" (movie),
谁又能度过《爱你九周半》那样的九周半呢
let alone a life time? The passion in the movies.
更不要说过一辈子了 那电影里的激情
Impossible standards.Also,self-help books.
都是不可能的标准 还有那些自助的书
"Think and Grow Rich".
比如《思考致富》
Nothing much about this.No,just think.And then you'll be rich.
和这个没什么关系 只要思考 就能致富
Tens of millions of copies sold from this book.
这本书卖了几百万本
Or here is another book that I found.
这里还有一本书
Now the book,the book may be great.
这本书或许不错
I haven't read it- I have to admit.
我得承认我还没有读过
But look at it- "Small Steps to Big Happiness.NOW!"
但先看看 《小步迈向幸福 现在》
Again,we can't wait.It's about the destination.
我们又迫不及待了 说的是专注于目标
It's not about the hard work,the journey,the character,
而不是专注于努力 旅途 人格
change that needs to take place.
还有所需的改变
And there is something else.
还有别的
There is something else that leads to perfectionism.
还有别的导致完美主义的因素
And this is the research that you have already read about.
这是一个你们已经读到过的研究结果
And this is work done by,great work done by Carol Dweck,
这是由Carol Dweck完成的出色研究
who is now at Stanford.
她现在在斯坦福大学工作
Here is her study.
这就是她的研究成果
Because you see,
因为
what she illustrates is that not all praise is good.
她所描述的是 不是所有的赞美都是好的
Telling a kid you are wonderful,you are terrific,you are great,
对一个孩子说 你很棒 你很出色
no matter what indiscriminately-
不吝赞美之词
you are so smart,you are so amazing,my little Einstein-
你太聪明了 你真是惊人 我的小爱因斯坦
that's not always good.
这也不总是好的
That may be harmful in the long run.
长期来看这可能也是有害的
And it may,it may create the perfectionism schema.
这也会导致完美主义的基模
So let me share with you one of her studies.
那么我和你们分享一下她的研究成果吧
And again,I think you've already read this.
我想你们已经读过了
So what she did was going to group of 10 years old
她所做的就是找到一些十岁的孩子
and randomly divided them into two groups.
然后把他们随机分成两组
The first group did a puzzle
第一组孩子都做了道题
which they completed successfully,each one individually.
他们都每个人独立完成了
And at the end,for each one when he or she completed the puzzle,
到最后 对每一个完成的孩子
she would say,"wow.You are so intelligent.So smart."
她都说"你真聪明伶俐"
And of course,they felt good about it.Terrific.
当然 孩子们都感觉不错
The second group did the exact same puzzle- succeeded; did well.
第二组做的是同一道题 做完了 做的不错
And at the end of it,she said,
结束后 她说
"wow.You put so much effort into it.You worked so hard."
"你真努力 你很认真"
Again,randomly divided into these two groups.
这随机分成的两组孩子
One- "smart and intelligent"; one- "effort,hard work".
一组是"聪明伶俐" 一组是"努力认真"
And she had a second part of the study.
然后她开始第二部分的研究
That second part:
第二部分
the participant had to choose between two puzzles.
两组孩子要选两道题
One puzzle they were told was relatively easy-
他们被告知其中一道很简单
one they could do well.
他们可以很好地完成
The other one was extremely hard,
另一道非常之困难
but they could really learn a lot from it.
但是他们能够从中学到许多
From the group that was told that
那组被称赞
they were smart or smart and intelligent,
聪明伶俐的孩子里
50 percent chose the easy one;
五成孩子选了简单的题目
50 percent chose the hard one where they could learn a lot.
五成孩子选择了可以学到很多的难题
From the group that was told that they were hard-working,
那组被称赞努力认真的孩子里
that they put in a lot of effort,90 percent chose the hard one,
九成孩子选择了
the one that they could learn from.
他们能学到很多的难题
This was the part two of the study.
这就是研究的第二部分
Part three.
第三部分
She brought them in again,and this time had them take,
这次她让孩子们做
or do a puzzle which was very difficult,
一道非常难的题
which was essentially unsolvable.
这题基本上是无法解答的
And she wanted to see the reaction of the two groups.
她想看看两组孩子的反应
The group that was told how smart they were,
被告知他们很聪明
how intelligent they were,
很伶俐的那一组
that group didn't persist much
他们没有坚持多久
and experienced a lot of frustration
并且非常沮丧
and would give up very quickly on that puzzle.
并且很快就开始放弃了
In contrast,the group that was told earlier that
与此相反 被告知努力认真的
they worked hard and that they put in a lot of effort,
那一组孩子
persisted much more and actually enjoyed the process,
他们更能坚持并且享受解题的过程
even though they didn't end up solving the puzzle.
即使到最后他们都没能解开这道题
But they enjoyed the process and they worked harder.
但是他们享受这个过程 并且更加努力
Look at this slight manipulation.
看看这微小的操纵带来的结果
Simply one sentence- "oh you are so smart!"
简简单单的一个句子"你真聪明"
"Oh you are working so hard!"
"你真努力"
One sentence lead to this significant difference.
一句话带来了这么明显的不同
In her words- "Emphasizing effort gives a child a variable
用她的话来说 "重视努力让孩子拥有
that they can control.
一个他自己能掌控的变量
They come to see themselves as in control of their success.
这能让他们认为自己能掌控自己的成功
Emphasizing natural intelligence
强调自然的天赋
takes it out of the child’s control,
让孩子们无法掌控成功
and it provides no good recipe for responding to a failure."
这不会给孩子提供面对失败的方法
Essentially what happens when you focus only on the intelligence,
事实上当你仅仅注重于天赋的时候
on how smart you are,you are creating the perfectionist schema,
你就是在制造完美主义的基模
as opposed to a schema that
而不是专注于
focuses on the journey,effort,hard work.
旅途当中 努力的基模
She continues-
她继续说道
"When you praise kids' in telligence and then they fail,
"如果你称赞孩子的智力 当他们失败时
they think they're not smart anymore,
他们会认为自己不再聪明
and they lose interest in their work.
然后失去对于眼前工作的兴趣
In contrast,kids praised for effort show no impairment
相反 那些被称赞努力的孩子
and often are energized in the face of difficulty."
在困难面前不会气馁 甚至更有动力
What a difference just based on these two approaches.
这两种方式造成了多么明显的不同
Person who is praised for their intelligence creates this schema-
被称赞智力的人会产生这样的基模
either I'm intelligent or I'm not.
要么我很聪明 要么我就不聪明
And I'm afraid of not being intelligent,
我很畏惧不聪明
so I'll choose the easier task.
所以我就选择容易一点的任务吧
And when I can't do something,it's an attack,
当我无法做到的时候 这就是攻击
it's an insult on my schema,right?
是对于我的基模的侮辱 没错吧
It's a deviation from this straight narrow.
这是对于直线的偏离
In contrast,if effort is most important,
相对的 如果努力才是最重要的
"OK,let me see what's around the corner here."
"好的 让我试试看吧"
"Hey I'm learning a lot now.This is wonderful.This is fun."
"我学到了很多 这真有意思"
Because with one,it's "a fixed mindset",in Dweck's words.
因为 一个是"既定思维模式"如Dweck所说
And in the other,
而另一个
it's the malleable,changing,ongoing,developing mindset.
是种可拓展的 时刻改变和发展的思维模式
One- there is fear of failure,cause I want to be smart.
一个是 畏惧失败 因为我想聪明
It's fun being called smart and intelligent.
被人称赞聪明很有意思
I don't want to threaten the schema.
我不想威胁到这个基模
Versus working hard,focusing on the process,
相对的是 努力的 重视过程的
when the excellence schema
当追求卓越的基模
becomes the dominant modus operandi.OK.
成为惯常做法
So how do we overcome perfectionism?
那么我们如何克服完美主义呢
What do we do about it if we have it?
如果我们确实有这个问题怎么办
And again,remember there's no perfect perfectionist.
要记住 根本就没有完美的完美主义者
There is no perfect person committed to excellence.
也没有完美的追求卓越者
You need to choose in your life where you are happy,
你们必须选择你能快乐的生活方式
and where you think you can be happier.
选择你认为能够更加快乐的生活方式
This may not even speak to you.
不会有现成的答案摆在你面前
This for you may be just interesting academically,
对你而言可能只是有趣的学术理论
or it may be deeply personal.
或者是非常个人化的原因
So how do we become more and more of the excellence schema?
那么我们该怎么更多地采用卓越的基模呢
First,it is about self-awareness.It's about understanding.
首先 是自我认知 在于自我了解
For me,a big breakthrough was understanding
对我来说 明白 "我太过于有自卫性了
"hey I'm actually defensive and I don't want to be defensive."
我不想再这样了"是一个大突破
Because I know that it hurts intimacy and relationships
因为我知道这会伤害亲密的人际关系
and that's when I started the real work on it.
并且从那时候我开始在这上面努力
And that has improved,
并且有所进步
and continues to improve my relationships.
并且在将来仍将继续提升我的人际关系
Or "look at my reaction to failure.
或者"看看我有多么畏惧失败
Look how afraid I am of hearing a no.
我有多么害怕听到个不字
Look how afraid I am of being rejected.
看看我有多么害怕被拒绝
Look how afraid I am of coping and trying."
看看我有多害怕应对与尝试"
So being aware of it.
就应该意识到它
I mean,if you want to improve your forehand in tennis,
如果你想让你的网球技术进步
you first need to be aware of what it is that you want to improve
你必须首先明白你想要进步的是什么
So that's the first step.And that's easier said than done.
这就是第一步 说起来容易做起来难
Let me show you a quick example of someone
我来给你们介绍一个简短的例子
who perhaps is not fully aware of her weaknesses.
是关于一个不完全了解自己的弱点的人的
[Video: Will and Grace S3EP10]
视频：威尔和格蕾丝 第三季第十集
KAREN: Hey,Jackie Brown.
你好 Jackie Brown
JACK: Why isn't there any coffee?!
为什么没有咖啡了
KAREN: Same reason why you don't have a wife and three kids.
和你没有老婆和三个孩子的原因相同
It's the way God wants it.
上帝决定的
JACK: Damn it,this is an office! There should be coffee!
该死的 这可是间办公室 应该有咖啡的
KAREN: Hey,hey,hey,hey,hey!
嗨 嗨
Why don't you save your anger for the bedroom,where it belongs?
为什么不把你的怒气留在卧室里呢
Why don't you go see your little coffee cutie,huh?
为什么你不去见你的咖啡小爱人呢
Your latte lover.Mr.Jock-full-of-nuts.
你的拿铁小情人 疯子先生
JACK: He quit,all right?
他辞职了 好吧
What is this? The freaking inquisition?
这是什么意思 你在审问我吗
Can't a guy have a nice,hot cup of coffee when he wants,
难道想喝咖啡时 就不能好好的喝一杯热咖啡吗
or do we all live in "Tea Land"
还是说我们都住在"茶之国度"里
where it's a capital crime to even say the word "coffee"?
只要提到"咖啡"就是犯罪
KAREN: Ok,jitterbug,get a hold of yourself.
好了 神经质 冷静一点
JACK: Don't tell me to get a hold of myself.I'm fine!
别让我冷静一点 我很好
KAREN: Ok,you may wanna take a look in the mirror
好吧 或许你想照照镜子
because you got a little crazy on your face.Ok?
因为你看起来有点疯 好吗
JACK: Oh,my God.
我的天啊
Karen,what's happening to me?
Karen 我到底是怎么了
KAREN: Well,I'm no expert,
好吧 我不是专家
but I think you have a little addiction problem.
但我觉得你是犯瘾了
No tears on the damask.
别把眼泪滴在台布上
JACK: Addiction? Oh,no.No,no!
犯瘾 不 不
I don't have an addiction,thank you very much.
我可没上瘾 多谢你了
KAREN: Ok,ok.JACK: I'm fine,I'm fine.
- 好的 好的   - 我没事 我没事
KAREN: Ok,ok,it's over.
好了 好了 都结束了
Now,listen to me.[KAREN GETS OUT A PILL.]
现在听我说 [Karen拿起药片]
The first thing you have to do is admit that you have a problem.
首先你要做的就是承认自己的问题
[KAREN SWIRLS THE PILL IN HER MARTINI.]
[Karen把药片放进酒里搅拌]
Because if you can't even recognize the signs...
因为如果你连症状都不能发觉
[KAREN DROPS THE WET PILL INTO HER MOUTH.]
[Karen把药片吞了]
Then you are really in sorry shape.
那你就真的糟糕了
[KAREN WASHES DOWN THE PILL.] Oh,mmm!
[Karen用酒送服药片]
[TO THE MARTINI GLASS] Why are you so good to me?
你怎么对我这么好呢
JACK: Karen,I can't do it.I'm hooked on the junk.
Karen 我办不到 我真的上瘾了
KAREN: Well,honey,if it'll help you,I'll do it with you,ok?
那么甜心 如果有作用的话 我就和你一起吧
I'll kick coffee,too.
我也戒咖啡了
Yeah! It won't be easy,but every morning when I wake up,
是啊 这不简单 但是每当我早上起床时
I'll just have to get used to drinking my Bailey's straight.
我只要习惯直接喝掉我的百利甜酒就好
It'll still be the best part of waking up.
那仍然会是起床最好的一刻
JACK: Ok,Karen.Ok.Together we can do this.
好的Karen 我们一起能做到的
Let me just have one last cup.
让我再喝一杯
KAREN: No.
不行
JACK: Half a cup.
半杯
KAREN: No.
不行
JACK: How about you drink a cup and I'll lick your tongue?
你喝一杯然后我舔你的舌头怎么样
KAREN: [BEAT] Tempting,but no.Ok,come here.Right here.
很诱人 但是不行 过来吧
JACK: Oh,Karen,when will the lambs stop screaming?
Karen 小羊们什么时候才能不叫啊
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:So whether it's dealing with addiction
不管是要应对上瘾问题
or dealing with any issue in our lives,perfectionism,
还是对于生活中别的问题 完美主义
or whether it's improving something,first step is awareness.
还是要改善什么 第一步就是要有意识
Second step is- there is 5 more minutes,by the way,
第二步是 还有五分钟就完
those of you who are looking at this clock- it's 5 minutes fast.
那些看着钟的同学 那钟快了五分钟
Or 4 more minutes.4 more minutes.Focus on a reward effort.
或是四分钟 还有四分钟就完 专注于对努力的嘉奖
What Carol Dweck showed was
Carol Dweck向我们展示的
when we focus on efforts,people's effort,
就是当我们专注于努力的时候
we are able to change schema that has been engrained there,
我们就能够改变那种根深蒂固的基模
and that has been there very often for years.
即便这种基模已经存在了多年
So with ourselves,or with other people,
所以对我们自己 或者对别人
it's about focusing on the journey,
我们应专注于旅途
focusing on and rewarding ourselves at times,
专注 并不时地嘉奖自己
even for failure,for trying.
甚至是嘉奖自己的失败 自己的尝试
And within a few hours,what Carol Dweck has seen,
在几个小时内 如Carol Dweck所见
teaching people that their mind is malleable,
告诉人们他们的心是可以拓展的
teaching them actually about neuro plasticity that is not a fix,
告诉他们神经可塑性 并非已经定型
we can bring about change.
我们仍可以作出改变
Active acceptance.
积极的接受
Karen Horney,
Karen Horney
whom I consider one of the mothers of positive psychology
我认为她是幸福学创始人之一
has done a lot of work on neurosis.
她在神经症领域做了很多工作
One of the thing that she found was that neurosis
她研究所得的其中一点是神经症
that we have never really goes away.
它从来不会消失
It's always part of us.
它总是我们的一部分
It becomes more manageable,but it's always there.
它会变得更加可控制 但是总是存在
And perfectionism at the extreme is a form of neurosis.
而极度的完美主义也是一种神经症
So the thing is to accept that it will always be...
所以关键就是接受它
I always have the tendency for perfectionism and it's OK.
我总会有完美主义倾向 但是这没关系
However,whereas before,
但是 在以前
I was here on the extreme of perfectionism;
我有着极度的完美主义
now I'm much closer to the excellence extreme.
现在我更加接近追求卓越的极致
And it's a life long...It's an on-going process.
这是持续一生的 是不断进行的一个过程
It's an on-going process.
这是不断进行的一个过程
And the key here is to accept that
所以现在的关键就是接受
it will always be part of one's life and then to say,
它一直都是我们生活的一部分这个事实
"all right,so what do I do now?"
然后问 "好的 那我该怎么办"
In other words,it is about then taking action.
换句话说就是采取行动
Behavior.
行为
So for example,it's about coping,putting ourselves on the line.
所以举例来说 就是怎么应对 把自己置于线上
What I did initially,
我最初所做的
when I first realized that perfectionism and my defensiveness,
在我留意到我的完美主义与自卫性的时候
I would go out of my way and solicit criticism.
我会撇开我的做法并且请求批评
And I would ask people,"so you know give me feedback about it."
我会问别人"给我点反馈吧"
And when I received negative feedback,
当我收到负面的反馈的时候
things that were actually deviations from the straight line,
和我的直线有所偏离的时候
I literally held myself from you know pouncing back.
我就阻止自己回击
You know the best form of defenses
你们也知道 对于完美主义者来说
is attack very often for perfectionist.
最好的防守就是进攻
And slowly I got used to it.And I became far less defensive.
慢慢地我就习惯了 我没那么有自卫性了
And I was able to create much higher levels of intimacy.
我得以创造更高层次的亲密关系
Or I put myself on the line in other areas,
或者我开始尝试别的领域
where I potentially would experience a no.
那里我可能会遭到否定
So let me end with a quick story.
让我以一个故事来结尾吧
Her name is Brittaney.She was a show girl.At least to me she was.
她的名字叫Brittaney 她是一个展示女郎
We met freshman week.And we really hit it off.
我们在大学第一周时认识 我对她一见钟情
We spent almost the entire freshman week out.
我们几乎整个第一周都在一起
And at the end of the freshman week,
到那一周的周末
wanting to overcome my perfectionism,
为了克服我的完美主义
I asked her out.And she said no.
我约她出来 她拒绝了
It surprised me,def me,hurt me.But she said no.
这让我很吃惊 很受伤 但是她确实拒绝了
My sophomore year,we met again.
在大学第二年 我们又见面了
And again,I asked her out.And this time she said no.
我再次约她出来 她又拒绝了
Junior year,toward the end of my junior year,I dated someone.
第三年 在年末的时候 我和另一个人约会了
So Brittaney was out of the equation.
所以Brittaney就出局了
And then we met again- my senior year.
然后我们又见面了 在我大四的时候
We had an amazing conversation.
我们谈了些有趣的话题
By that time I already studied psychology.
那时候我已经开始学习心理学了
I could also read her body language.
我也可以读懂她的身体语言
She did a lot of this with her hair.
她经常这么弄她的头发
And I knew that she really liked me.
然后我知道她确实很喜欢我
And I asked her out.And she said no.
然后我约她出来 她拒绝了
And I'm still here with you.
然后我就还留在这里和你们在一起
And that was an important learning process.
这就是个很重要的学习过程
Learn to fail or fail to learn.
学会失败 或败于学习
I'll see you in next week.
我们下周见